Kōnstantinos Apostolou Doxiadēs Papers
Kōnstantinos Apostolou Doxiadēs Papers
1958-1966.
Doxiadēs, Kōnstantinos Apostolou, 1913-1975.
1 linear ft.
The papers of the Greek architect and city planner contain articles by and about Doxiadēs, pamphlets, and interviews.
148950
Biographical History
Dr. Kōnstantinos Apostolou Doxiadēs (1913-1975), an architect-planner, was born in Stenimachos, Greece, on May 14, 1913. He graduated as an architect-engineer from the Technical University of Athens in 1935. After studying at the Berlin-Charlottenburg University in Germany until 1936, he married Emma Scheeper in 1940; they had four children. Doxiados received an LL.D. from Swarthmore College in the United States in 1962 and was at Mills College until 1964. He received an L.H.D. from Wayne State University and went to Northern Michigan University in 1965.
In 1948, Doxiadēs was made minister-coordinator of the Greek Recovery Program for the following three years. In 1951, he became president of Doxiadēs Associates, a consultant in development and ekistics, in Athens. In 1958, he began teaching at the Athens Technical Institute, as a professor of ekistics in its Graduate School of Ekistics. Doxiadēs was a visiting lecturer at the universities of Chicago, Yale, Harvard, Princeton, Southern California, Swarthmore College, and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. His honors include the Greek Military Cross(1941), officer of the Order of the British Empire(1954), the Sir Patrick Abercrombie prize of the International Union of Architects(1963), and others. He was an honorary corresponding fellow of the Royal Incorporated Architects of Scotland and an honorary corresponding member of the Town Planning Institute of Great Britain.
Doxiadēs was also a distinguished author. He wrote many books, mainly in Greek, including March of the People(1949), Our Capital and Its Future(1960), and Architecture in Transition(1963), in English. He also wrote reports on development and ekistics in some thirty countries.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Kōnstantinos Apostolou Doxiadēs Papers span 1958-1996 and include a Bibliography (1 folder) of articles written about Dr. Doxiadēs, one letter of Outgoing correspondence (1 folder), Manuscripts (2 folders) of an article by and an interview with Dr. Doxiadēs, and Published materials (1.5 boxes) including books, magazine articles, an interview, and pamphlets.
Subject and Genre Headings
Architects; Doxiadēs, Kōnstantinos Apostolou, 1913-1975.; Architects.; Architecture -- United States -- 20th century.; City planners.; Articles.; Interviews.; Pamphlets.; Architects.; City planners.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Doxiadēs, 1965-1970.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing
    - 1965 (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Article by
    - Written for "Kopusai-Kentiku", 1965 (Box 1)
  - Interview
    - European Recovery Program Interview, 1964 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Books by
    - Architecture in Transition, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Arquitectura en Transicion, 1963 (Box 1)
    - The New World of Urban Man, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Interview
    - Meet the Press, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Magazine articles by
    - 1965-1966, 1962, undated (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets by
    - 1958-1960 (Box 1)
    - 1962 (Box 2)
    - 1963 (Box 2)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 2)